Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 13.
We are asked to find the complexity of as prime method it is of bullion returning type and it took in
meters and and so we have a for loop and the starting condition from X equal to two.
And the stopping condition at X less than or equal to square root of N and X plus plus post the video
and think about this algorithm.
I hope you write down and solve this question and more exercises as you solve as you practice more.
You will get a master, you will be a master in data structure and algorithms because solving more exercises
will be making you better thinking better thinker better.
Problem solved, OK?
And these questions are, by the way, from interviews and real interviews.
OK, I want from you.
To recall that if we have X Plus Plus here, so we have all elements, we are going to go all through
all elements from to to less than square root of.
So these elements.
This loop will go through all the elements from.
Do tell square root of and so the square root of and is radical.
This is a function that get that calculated the square root of.
OK.
If M modulo X this is X equal, equal to zero, then return false.
This is of one.
Returning and this one is of one, and the return true is of one.
So.
That that determined the algorithm is on the initial condition and the stopping condition and the way
of increment of a loop, so the loop here will determine the algorithm that algorithm time complexity.
Let's take an example of taking an equal and equal to like.
16.
OK.
Now, let's solve this exercise.
We start from X equal to two.
X equal to do and X and X less than square root of N.
Square root of and radical and.
Let me make this.
I put X here.
And here.
And let's try to solve this today.
Always, when you want to solve like these exercises and get the pattern set, take an example.
OK?
We took an example and equal to 60.
We start the iteration of the first iteration X equal to two x less than square root of N.
Square root of and would be equal to four.
OK, so the square root of an is four.
OK.
Do less than four.
Yes, so go and execute this method.
It would be like making the calculations.
OK, now it will finish here, increase x by one going up three is X now, and the square root of 16
is four.
So three less than four yet or equal to four?
Yes, go and execute.
It goes here and going up above two will go up to here and start making the conditions for comparing
the conditions for now x equal to four and X for less than or equal four.
Yes, because square root of 16 is four and for less than or equal to four.
Yes.
So go and execute this.
Now it is.
It goes here and going up X is is increased by one.
So X is now five.
Five is less than or equal to four.
No.
So it will be stopped now when putting like this table, we see the pattern.
How many times it would be executed, it being executed like three times.
OK.
So.
Three times.
But the limiting behavior we are going to go through from two, three and four, so all the elements
are being executed from X, this is the range from X to radical and.
OK.
And X would be from two to radical.
This is the range, if an equal to twenty five, it would be executed.
How many times it would be executed five times or forty five times?
Yes.
Goes radical.
Twenty five is equal to five.
It would be two, three, four and five.
OK.
Sorry, four times.
So it is increasing according to the radical end.
OK.
And it starts from two, so.
The radical and.
Is this thumping behavior and it is the limiting and all this since we are going to throw and loop through
all the elements still finding the radical end that called time complexity of executing this algorithm
is of radical and.
OK.
This is the limiting behavior.
This is the time complexity.
This is the stopping condition of this algorithm and the radical end.
So always take two examples in order to get the pattern in order to get their mathematical sequence
that the algorithm.